

Ali Asghar Momeni Vesalian

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - JAVA

PROFILE

Gender: Male

Nationality: Iranian **Birth Date**: 6/30/1985

Software engineer with a strong background in design and development on Java platform. Keen learner and problem solver with a passion for algorithms, architecture, high throughput systems and Big Data. Highly experienced in developing financial and banking systems.

EDUCATION

Master of Science from Tehran Markazi Azad University in Software Engineering from September 2015 to Present.

Bachelor of Science from Qazvin Azad University in Software Engineering from September 2003 to September 2008.

LANGUAGES

English

Persian

CONTACT

Email: momeni.vesalian@gmail.com

Mobile: +98 912 020 6542

LinkedIn: Momeni Vesalian's profile Address: Flat 1, No. 5, Layeqi Alley, Qasr-od-Dasht St., Azarbayejan St.,

Tehran, Iran

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sava Arman Kish (Bitex)

Senior Java Developer

June 2018 - Present

- I currently work as the chief architect of the exchange project.
- I design architecture model and implement architectural APIs.
- I design and implement matching engine.

Navaco (Maskan Bank)

Senior Java Developer

Mar 2017 - June 2018

- I worked as a member of CORE Banking architecture team.
- I designed architecture model and implemented some architectural APIs.
- I designed and implemented lending overnight calculation.

Caspian (Parsian Bank)

Senior Java Developer and Designer

Sep 2014 - Mar 2017

- I worked as a member of Lending team.
- I designed and implemented conversion's architecture model.
- I wrote 30000+ lines of Java and PL-SQL code.

Rayan Eghtesad Novin (Eghtesad Novin Bank)

Software Designer

May 2013 - Sep 2014

- I worked as a member of Lending team.
- I designed repayment and settlement functionalities.

Caspian (Parsian Bank)

Java Developer and Designer

Sep 2009 - May 2013

- I worked as a member of Lending team.
- I designed and implemented repayment, settlement, installment calculation.
- I wrote 150000+ lines of Java code.

IT and Communication Organization of Tehran Municipality

Java Developer

Oct 2008 - Sep 2009

- I worked as a member of Media Observatory team.
- I implemented several functionalities.



Ali Asghar Momeni Vesalian

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - JAVA

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Java 8	Spring
Design Patterns	Spring Boot
SOA	Spring MVC
Microservices	Spring Batch
Event Driven Architecture	Spring Security
Software Architecture Patterns	Spring Data / JPA
Big Data Architecture	Hibernate / EclipseLink / iBatis
Big Data Concepts	Vert.x
Live Migration	Redis
Concurrent Programming	Oracle PL/SQL Development
Reactive Programming	Gradle / Maven
RESTful Web Services	Git / Subversion
Docker and Docker Compose	Test Driven Development
CI / CD	JUnit / Power Mock / JMockit
Jenkins	Hadoop / Spark / Storm
Swagger	UML / Agile and RUP Methodologies
Eureka / Ribbon / Hystrix Netflix	CORE Banking Systems
OSGi / Blueprint	Lending System Developer
Apache Karaf	Crypto Currency Exchanges
JAAS	Exchange Developer
<u>I</u> ATEX	